<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Hart on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Hart on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Periyazhvar Thiruppallaṇḍu &amp; Thirumozhi (pāsurams 1- 473)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/01_tiruppallaNDu_tirumOLHi_pEriyaLHvar_1-473/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/01_tiruppallaNDu_tirumOLHi_pEriyaLHvar_1-473/</guid>
      <description>Praising the god
Let us praise the god and say, “Pallāṇḍu! Pallāṇḍu!” He, colored like a blue sapphire, conquered his enemies with his strong arms. We praise him forever, forever and forever and for many crores of years. Protect us as we are beneath your divine feet.
Let us praise the god and say, “Pallāṇḍu! Pallāṇḍu!” Let us live never apart from his devotees and him. Let us praise the beautiful Lakshmi seated on the right side of his strong chest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Aṇḍal : Thiruppāvai (474 -503)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/02_aNDal_tiruppAvai_474-503/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/02_aNDal_tiruppAvai_474-503/</guid>
      <description>Girls waking up their friends.
The girls come and wake up their friends. They say, “Today is the auspicious full moon day of Markazhi month. O you adorned with beautiful ornaments, let us go bathe. Come! We are the beloved young girls of the flourishing cowherd village. Nārāyaṇan, the son of Nandagopan, who looks after the cows with a sharp spear, the young lion of lovely-eyed Yashoda with a dark body, beautiful eyes and a face bright as the shining moon will give us the Paṛai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Aṇḍal : Nāchiyār Thirumozhi (504-646)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/03_aNDal_nAChiyAr_tirumOLHi_504-646/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/03_aNDal_nAChiyAr_tirumOLHi_504-646/</guid>
      <description>The cowherd women worship Kāma, the god of love.
We clean the floor in the month of Thai and decorate it with beautiful kolams. In the month of Masi we use soft white powder and make lovely decorations in our front yard. O Kamadeva, I worship you and your brother Saman. I wonder, can I survive this love sickness? Give me the boon of belonging to the lord of Thiruvenkaṭam holding a discus in his hand that throws out fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Perumāl Thirumozhi by Kulasekharazhvar (647 -751)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/04_pErumAl_tirumOLHi_by_kulasEkharaLHvar_647-751/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/04_pErumAl_tirumOLHi_by_kulasEkharaLHvar_647-751/</guid>
      <description>When will I see my god, the lord of Thiruvarangam
When will the day come when my two eyes see the dark god shining like a komalam jewel, resting on his beautiful white shining bed, the king of snakes with a thousand shining foreheads that remove the darkness with their bright diamonds, as the god’s feet are washed by the clear water of the Ponni river flowing in the Thiruppadi of Srirangam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Thirumazhisai Azhvar Thiruchanda Virutham (752 -871)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/05_tirumaLHisai-ALHvAr_tiruChanda_virutham_752-871/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/05_tirumaLHisai-ALHvAr_tiruChanda_virutham_752-871/</guid>
      <description>Chanda kali virutham. Who is God? What is God? What is the nature of God?
You are five things—taste, light, touch, sound and smell in earth. You are four things—taste, light, feeling of touch, and sound in water. You are three things—taste, light and heat in fire. You are two things—the touch and the sound of the wind. You are the unique ancient one. You are many things on the earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Thirumālai : Thoṇḍaraḍippoḍi Azhvar (872-916)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/06_tirumAlai_thONDaraDippODi-ALHvAr_872-916/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/06_tirumAlai_thONDaraDippODi-ALHvAr_872-916/</guid>
      <description>You, the ancient one, swallowed the three worlds and spit them out. We do not like the feeling that come from the enjoyment of our five senses and we do not sin anymore. The messengers of Yama cannot hurt us now. We are brave because we have learned your names and recite them, O god of Srirangam.
Your body is like a beautiful green hill, your lotus eyes are handsome and your mouth is red as coral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Thiruppaḷḷi Ezhuchi - Thoṇḍaraḍippoḍi Azhvar (917-926)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/07_tiruppaLLiy-ELHuChi_thONDaraDippODi-ALHvAr_917-926/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/07_tiruppaLLiy-ELHuChi_thONDaraDippODi-ALHvAr_917-926/</guid>
      <description>When the sun rises in the east from the peak of the mountain and darkness has gone and it is morning and all the beautiful flowers that drip honey bloom, the gods of the sky all come before you to worship you. Elephants, male and female, come and, as drums are beaten, it seems the sound of a roaring ocean spreads everywhere. O dear god of Srirangam, wake up and give us your grace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Amalan Aadipirān - Thiruppāṇāzhvār (927-936)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/08_amalan_aadipirAn-tiruppANALHvAr_927-936/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/08_amalan_aadipirAn-tiruppANALHvAr_927-936/</guid>
      <description>He, the faultless one, the king of the gods in the sky who gives us his grace and makes us his devotees, is pure, the lord of the Thiruvenkaṭam hills surrounded with fragrant groves. He is the god of justice in the sky, and the dear one of Srirangam surrounded by tall walls. His lotus feet came and entered my sight.
He is pleasant and joyful measured the world, growing so tall that his crown touched the sky, and as Rāma of the Kakutstha dynasty he killed the Rakshasas with his cruel arrows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Kaṇṇiṇuṭchiṛuthāmbu Madhurakavi Azhvar (937-947)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/09_kaNNiNuTChi.DuthAmbu_madhurakavi-ALHvAr_937-947/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/09_kaNNiNuTChi.DuthAmbu_madhurakavi-ALHvAr_937-947/</guid>
      <description>I praise the god, the divine Māyan, my father, who was tied by Yashoda with a small rope. If I approach the place where the Nambi of south Kuruhur stays and say his name, nectar will spring from my tongue.
I praise him with my tongue and relish it. I yearn for the golden feet of Nambi of Thirukkuruhur and I know no other god but Nambi of Thirukuruhur. I wander and sing sweet songs about him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 Thirukkurundānḍagam -- Thirumangaiyāzhvār (2032 -2051)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/11_tirukkurundAnDagam--tirumangaiyALHvAr_2032-2051/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/11_tirukkurundAnDagam--tirumangaiyALHvAr_2032-2051/</guid>
      <description>I bow and praise him, the wise Thirumāl, a treasure, a coral pillar, my fate. He killed Kamsan to protect the world. If the devotees think of him as a true path, he will give them moksha, and I am his devotee and he has entered my heart. I will not leave him.
The lord is the earth, wind, water, fire, the sky, a beautiful shining jewel, nectar, a river of joy for his devotees, Yama for the Asuras and he stays in the Himalayas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Thiruneḍunthāṇḍagam - Thirumangaiyāzhvār (2052 – 2081)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/12_tirunEDunthANDagam-tirumangaiyALHvAr_2052_2081/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/12_tirunEDunthANDagam-tirumangaiyALHvAr_2052_2081/</guid>
      <description>This book is divided into three parts.
Praise of the god . A mother speak about her daughter who loves Kaṇṇan. The daughter who loves Kaṇṇan talks about her love with her friend. Praising god Shining like lightning, he is the four Vedas, the light of a lamp, the rising crescent moon, the past and the future. Without sickness, old age, birth or death, he is gold and diamond and shines as the five elements–earth, water, fire, wind and sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 Mudal Thiruvandādi - Poyhai Azhvar (2082 – 2181)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/13_mudal_tiruvandAdi-pOyhai-ALHvAr_2082_2181/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/13_mudal_tiruvandAdi-pOyhai-ALHvAr_2082_2181/</guid>
      <description>The world is a lamp for me, wide ocean is its ghee, and the warm sun is its light. I place this garland of words on the feet of the lord with a shining discus and ask him to take me from the ocean of sorrow.
I do not know when you churned the milky ocean or when the whole earth was surrounded with the seas, all I know is that the world is created by you and you swallowed and spat it out at the end of the eon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14 Second Thiruvanthaathi Buthaththāzhvar (2182 -2281)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/14_iraNDAm_tiruvanthaathi_buthaththALHvar_2182-2281/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/14_iraNDAm_tiruvanthaathi_buthaththALHvar_2182-2281/</guid>
      <description>My love for him is a lamp, the oil in the lamp is my desire to worship him, and the wick is my sweet mind that melts for him. I light the shining lamp with my wisdom. I composed this Thiruvandāthi for Naraṇan in divine Tamil.
If you stay in a good place and recite the names of Nāraṇan, understanding him well with your wisdom, the nature of the king of the gods is to give you the privilege of being a god among the gods in the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15 Third Thiruvandādi – Peyāzhvār (2282 – 2381)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/15_third_tiruvandAdi_pEyALHvAr_2282_2381/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/15_third_tiruvandAdi_pEyALHvAr_2282_2381/</guid>
      <description>I saw today the divine form of the ocean-colored lord, his golden body adorned with jewels that shone with the color of the bright sun and the golden discus in his hands that fights in war and the sounding curving conch.
Today I saw his ankleted feet and now I will not be born again for seven births. O Thirumāl with a mountain-like golden chest , You are adorned with a cool thulasi garland, and you embrace your beloved Lakshmi from the milky ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16 Thirumazhisai Alvar - Nāmuhan Thiruvandāthi (2382 – 2477)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/16_nAmuhan_tiruvandAthi_tirumaLHisai_2382_2477/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/16_nAmuhan_tiruvandAthi_tirumaLHisai_2382_2477/</guid>
      <description>Nārāyaṇan created Nānmuhan. Nānmuhan created Shiva. O, heart! If we say this we will survive. Praise the feet of the poet Thirumzhisai.
Nārāyaṇan created Nānmuhan and Nānmuhan created the five-faced Sankaran. I composed andadi poems praising him. Learn and understand the deep meaning of each of these pāsurams without omission.
People say if one searches for a god, they will find only one god whose greatness no one knows. The search and the meaning of all things is the only our god.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17 Thiruvirutham - Nammāzhvar (2478 -2577)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/17_tiruvirutham-nammALHvar_2478-2577/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/17_tiruvirutham-nammALHvar_2478-2577/</guid>
      <description>The poet says, “O lord, chief of the gods in the sky, hear the request of your devotee. Remove my false knowledge, bad behavior, and unclean body and give me your grace so that I, born from my mother’s womb, will not be born in this world again.”
Her friend says, “She loves the cloud-colored Kaṇṇan, the god of the gods in the sky. Her eyes are filled with tears, as if she were a fish frolicking in the water of a flourishing pond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18 Nammaazhvar - Thiruvāsiriyam (2578 -2584)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/18_tiruvAsiriyam_nammaaLHvar_2578-2584/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/18_tiruvAsiriyam_nammaaLHvar_2578-2584/</guid>
      <description>Praising the god O lord, with red garments, your crown is the sun that spreads bright rays and the beautiful moon floats above your head. Your mouth is as lovely as coral and you shine like a light and an emerald hill. You are adorned with golden clothes and many precious ornaments and your mouth and eyes shine, adding to the luster of your dark body. You rest on thousand-headed Adisesha in the middle of ocean with rolling waves as Shiva, Nānmuhan who stays on a lotus on your navel, Indra and all the crowd of gods worship you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19 Nammāzhvar’s Periya Thiruvanthādi (2585 – 2671)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/19_periya-tiruvandAdi_nammALHvar_2585_2671/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/19_periya-tiruvandAdi_nammALHvar_2585_2671/</guid>
      <description>O heart! If you want to see him, get ready and come. Let us go together and praise with good words the divine nature and fame of the god colored like a kāyām flower.
Sometimes we praise you sometimes we blame you, sometimes we do not praise you and sometimes we do not blame you. Sometimes we disrespect you. sometimes we do not disrespect you, O lovely-eyed Thirumāl, don&amp;rsquo;t get angry at us even though we have done bad karma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 Thirumangai Azhvar - Thiruvezukuṛṛirukkai (2672)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/20_tiruveLHuku.D.Dirukkai_tirumangai-ALHvAr_2672/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/20_tiruveLHuku.D.Dirukkai_tirumangai-ALHvAr_2672/</guid>
      <description>This is only one Pasuram. You created Brahma on a large lotus on your navel, and you shot your fiery arrows and conquered and burned Lanka surrounded with strong forts around which even the sun and moon cannot move.
You took the form of a dwarf, a Brahmin bachelor dressed in deerskin, wore a shining string on your chest and went to Mahābali’s sacrifice. You asked the king for three feet of land and measured all the three worlds and the sky with your two feet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21 Siriya thirumaḍal - Thirumangaiyāzhvār (2673 to 2712)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/21_siriya_tirumaDal_tirumangaiyALHvAr_2673-2712/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/21_siriya_tirumaDal_tirumangaiyALHvAr_2673-2712/</guid>
      <description>Numbers of the Pasurams in this section follows Venkataraghavan’s text and is divided into 40 Pasurams.
The earth goddess
This world says, “Hills covered with clouds are the breasts of the earth goddess, the wide oceans are her clothes the bright sun is her thilagam, wide rivers are the ornaments on her ample chest, large dark clouds are her hair, and the ocean is her boundary. She is three things, dharma, wealth and moksha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22 Periyathirumaḍal - Thirumangai (2713 -2790)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/22_periyatirumaDal_tirumangai_2713-2790/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/22_periyatirumaDal_tirumangai_2713-2790/</guid>
      <description>(78 Pāsurams) God in his yogic sleep on the ocean.
As his bright emerald earrings throw out light, the lord is like a large mountain resting on the dotted snake Adisesha with shining jewels on his thousand divine heads The crowded stars in the sky shine and cover him like an umbrella.(1)
The sun and moon are his lights and the waves of the ocean fan him. (2)
The Earth goddess</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23 Thiruvāymozhi - Nammāzhvār (2791 – 3892)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/23_tiruvAymOLHi-nammALHvAr_2791_3892/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/23_tiruvAymOLHi-nammALHvAr_2791_3892/</guid>
      <description>O my heart! The matchless god of the gods in the sky who has unlimited goodness never grows tired of protecting the world. Removing my ignorance he gave me abundant knowledge. Worship his shining feet that take away all sorrows.
The ageless lord who is full of goodness and keeps Nānmuhan on a lotus on his chest removes the faults in your mind. There is no limit to what he can think and he is not attracted by any feelings of the senses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24 Rāmānujanutrandadi /Thiruvarangathamudanār (3893 -4000)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/24_rAmAnujanutrandadi__tiruvarangathamudanAr_3893-4000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/hart/24_rAmAnujanutrandadi__tiruvarangathamudanAr_3893-4000/</guid>
      <description>(Important Note. All the pasurams of Divayaprabandham from 1 to 3892 by twelve (eleven?) azhvars only praise the god of Vaishnavism? But the last 108 pasurams are confusing that are composed by Thiruvarangathamudanar who was probably lived in later century than 9CE. Most of the pasurams in this text seem to praise the god and probably Ramanujar. One wonders when they say whether they say &amp;lsquo;Ramanuja?&amp;rsquo; they really mean Rāmānujar? or the god.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
