<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;07 - Seventh Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;07 - Seventh Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Ul nilaviya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/01_Ul_nilaviya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/01_Ul_nilaviya/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.1 In Bhagavad Gītā (7-14), the Lord stated that those who take refuge in Him alone can get beyond Māyā (Prakṛti). Then and then only, the ‘Prakṛti’ helps towards liberation instead of hindering by concealing the real nature of the Lord. The net woven around each individual soul by the Almighty Lord, in the light of past Karma, has to be disentangled by Him alone, seeing that we are much-too-feeble and cannot disentangle even the nest built by a frail bird, in the manner it does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Kankulum Pakalum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/02_Kankulum_Pakalum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/02_Kankulum_Pakalum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.2 Towards the end of the sixth centum, we saw the Āḻvār surrendering himself at the feet of the Lord at Tiruvēṅkaṭam. Finding, however, that he was still lingering in this material world, dominated by the unruly senses, he cried out his fears in the last decad. like unto a child crying out from the tiger’s jaws, facing the mother standing in front. The Lord was, no doubt, well aware of the intensity of the Āḻvār’s God-love and his deep yearning to get out of the material shackles with no further delay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Vellaic curi cankotu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/03_Vellaic_curi_cankotu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/03_Vellaic_curi_cankotu/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.3 The bliss of the union of the Nāyaki and Lord Raṅganātha having overflown its continents, the Lord hit upon a method whereby the enjoyment could be stabilised instead of the Nāyaki being swept off by its exuberance. He went to Tentiruppēreyil, near the Āḻvār’s birth-place, game-hunting by way of relieving the distress of the people over there from the depredations of wild animals. The Nāyaki herself equipped Him with weapons, went with Him straight to the outer gate and bid Him farewell, wishing Him success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Ali ela</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/04_Ali_ela/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/04_Ali_ela/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.4 Just when the Nāyakī was attempting to go to Tiruppēreyil where the Lord had gone for game-hunting, He returned victorious, like Śrī Rāma back home from exile, after vanquishing Rāvaṇa and his formidable horde of Rākṣasas. It may be recalled that Sītā locked Śrī Rāma in her sweet embrace by way of nursing wounds on His person after His remarkable victory over Kara, Dhūṣaṇa, Triśiras and the fourteen thousand Rākṣasas under them, singlehanded and in an amazingly short space of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Karpar-irama-piranai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/05_Karpar-irama-piranai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/05_Karpar-irama-piranai/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.5 The Āḻvār, who revelled in the last decad, recounting some of the Lord’s glorious deeds, cites some more achievements of the Lord’s glorious deeds, cites some more achievements of the Lord in this decad, much to his own delectation. At the same time, he could not help wondering how the worldlings, whose birthright it is to share this enjoyment, kept aloof and he even felt vexed with them for their callous indifference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Pa maru muvulakum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/06_Pa_maru_muvulakum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/06_Pa_maru_muvulakum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.6 In the last decad, the Saint’s address to the world is implicit, although the third person has been used throughout, instead of the second. No doubt, the worldlings kept aloof from God because of their exclusive absorption in sensual pleasures, totally shorn of God-love. But then, here is the Āḻvār with an enormous yearning for the Lord, of unimaginable depth and yet, he has not been able to experience the bliss of lasting communion with Him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Elaiyar avo</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/07_Elaiyar_avo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/07_Elaiyar_avo/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.7 The soul-stirring utterances of the Saint, as in the last decad, should indeed have gone straight to the Lord in Heaven. In a way, the Lord would seem to have pacified the Āḻvār by enabling him to comprehend mentally His exquisite Form, limb by limb. Led away by the Lord’s charming beauty, the Āḻvār, aims at physical enjoyment of the Lord’s exquisite Form, with outstretched hands and feels frustrated when such an experience is denied to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Maya! Vamanane!</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/08_Maya_Vamanane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/08_Maya_Vamanane/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.8 In the last decad, the Alvar felt tormented by the mental vision of the Lord’s limbs, one after the other, rousing his appetite for God-enjoyment all the more. The Lord would not, however, fulfil the Āḻvār’s aspiration even now and is obviously waiting for the appropriate moment of consummation. The Āḻvār knows the Lord’s mind all right but still he is egged on by the exuberance of his God-love to crave for immediate union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Enraikkum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/09_Enraikkum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/09_Enraikkum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.9 It was indeed the Lord’s ingenuity that was in full evidence in the last decad, whereby He could gain time and divert the attention of the Āḻvār, astounded by the bewildering net-work of His superb wonders. In fact, we have seen this kind of happening all along, the appeasement of the Āḻvār at every turn by the Lord, exhibiting one or the other of His special traits and prolonging his stay in this abode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Inpam payakka</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/10_Inpam_payakka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/07_-_Seven/10_Inpam_payakka/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro7.10 In the last decad, the Āḻvār, who thought in terms of repaying the Lord’s kindness in choosing him, of all persons, for the sacred mission of singing ‘Tiruvāymoḻi’, was bewildered on finding nothing, he could offer unto the Lord, for there wasn’t anything he could call his own and the Lord, who is above wants of any kind, would need anything from him either. The merciful Lord would not, however, keep a devotee of such a high order in a state of mental torture.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
