<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;08 - Eighth Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;08 - Eighth Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Tevimar avar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/01_Tevimar_avar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/01_Tevimar_avar/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro8.1 In the last decad, the Āḻvār longed for the pleasure of singing Tiruvāymoḻi before the Divine couple at Tiruvāṟaṉviḷai and rendering unto Them other kinds of service as well. But then, the project did not get off the ground and non-fulfilment of his cherished desire made the Āḻvār grow sceptical of the Lord’s bonafides and His ability to concede the wish of His devotees. This doubt is expressed in this decad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Nankal varivalai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/02_Nankal_varivalai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/02_Nankal_varivalai/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.2 In the last decad, the Āḻvār began to suspect that, with his coming into the world, the Lord’s reputation as the repository of many an auspicious trait and the grand ordainer of all things, was becoming extinct. The Āḻvār was, however, brought back to normal thinking by the Lord and the Āḻvār’s misgivings were cleared up in a way. But then, the external perception of the Lord’s exquisite Form and physical contact, longed for by the Saint, did not, as yet, materialise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Ankum inkum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/03_Ankum_inkum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/03_Ankum_inkum/</guid>
      <description>8.3.1 Tamil text and transliteration:
அங்கும் இங்கும் வானவர் தானவர் யாவரும்
எங்கும் இனையைஎன்று உன்னைஅறியகிலாதுஅலற்றி
அங்கம்சேரும் பூமகள் மண்மகள் ஆய்மகள்
சங்குசக்கரக் கையவன் என்பர் சரணமே. (2)
aṅkum iṅkum vāṉavar tāṉavar yāvarum
eṅkum iṉaiyaieṉṟu uṉṉaiaṟiyakilātualaṟṟi
aṅkamcērum pūmakaḷ maṇmakaḷ āymakaḷ
caṅkucakkarak kaiyavaṉ eṉpar caraṇamē. (2)
English translation of verse 8.3.1:
The Vāṉavar, Tāṉavar and all else, here, there and everywhere,
Can hardly comprehend You but reckon You, in their own way.
Merely as their Saviour, in times of need,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Var kata aruvi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/04_Var_kata_aruvi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/04_Var_kata_aruvi/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.4 The Lord’s presence, in this dark land, alone and unaided, excited the reasonable fear of the Āḻvār that the worldlings would approach Him only to achieve their own selfish ends, with little or no care or love for Him. No doubt, the Lord allayed the Āḻvār’s fears, as we saw towards the end of the last decad. Still, the Lord has a lingering doubt that, in the exuberance of the Āḻvār’s love for Him, he might once again entertain similar fears about His safety and feel agitated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Mayak kutta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/05_Mayak_kutta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/05_Mayak_kutta/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.5 In the third decad of this centum, the Āḻvār grew apprehensive of the safety of the Lord of exquisite charm, moving along in this wicked land alone and unattended. The Āḻvār could, however, regain his composure, shaking off the fear in question, on the assurance given by the Lord, vide VIII-3-10. The following decad revealed an Āḻvār, fully relieved of his erstwhile fears, but the intense mental enjoyment of the Lord’s regal Form, enchanting every inch, resorted to by the Āḻvār in VIII-4-7, once again resulted in a deep yearning, an insatiable longing for external perception of the Lord’s Form, as envisioned by him and getting locked in His sweet embrace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Elliyum kalaiyum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/06_Elliyum_kalaiyum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/06_Elliyum_kalaiyum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.6 The Āḻvār’s yearning, in the last decad, was indeed too deep for words. At the same time, it has to be stressed that, if the Jñāni loves God dearly, He loves the Jñāni even more. And so, the Lord’s love for the Āḻvār also defies description. Stung by a deep sense of remorse over His laxity in not responding to the Āḻvār’s invitation, the Lord pondered over the step to be taken by Him to placate the Āḻvār.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Iruttum, viyantu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/07_Iruttum_viyantu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/07_Iruttum_viyantu/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.7 The bliss enjoyed by the Āḻvār in this decad, stands on a pedestal of its own. It can even be asserted that there is no comparable decad in the whole hymnal.
When one pauses and ponders which indeed is the greater of the two pulls, namely, the Lord’s effort to get at the Āḻvār and the Āḻvār’s desire to get at Him, it will be seen that the Lord exerts the greater, naturally, the stronger pull, His desire to get at the subject, His coveted belonging, being supreme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Kankal civantu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/08_Kankal_civantu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/08_Kankal_civantu/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.8 In the fifth decad of this centum (Māyak kūttā), the Āḻvār’s yearning was too deep for words. The Lord responded with even greater avidity and the two of them got wrapt up in mutual delight. The Āḻvār gave vent to his jubilation in the last decad, and even so, in the eighth song of that decad, he referred to himself as a frail being, with whom the great Lord of unlimited prowess has chosen to mingle freely and stay on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Karu manikka malai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/09_Karu_manikka_malai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/09_Karu_manikka_malai/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.9 This decad is spelt out by a mate of Parāṅkuśa Nāyakī (Āḻvār, figuratively turned into a female lover). In the entire hymnal, there are three decads of this type and this is the last of the series, the two earlier ones being IV-6 and VI-5. In IV-6, the mate advised the elders, gathered around Parāṅkuśa Nāyakī, who were treading the mis-guided path of invoking minor deities to cure the Nāyakī’s malady, to desist from their wrong methods and smear the Nāyakī’s body with the dust from the feet of Śrī Vaiṣṇavas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Netumarku atimai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/10_Netumarku_atimai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/08_-_Eight/10_Netumarku_atimai/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.10 The subject’s exclusive dependence on the Supreme Lord was emphasised in the last decad. But then, dependence on the Lord could extend upto the Lord’s devotees as well by virtue of His unbounded love for them. This is like our wearing on our heads, the holy sandals of the Lord and swallowing the water obtained by giving them a sacramental bath. Did not Tirumaṅkai Āḻvār declare in VIII-10-3 of his ‘Periya Tirumoḻi’ that, as a result of learning the eight-syllabled Tirumantra, he became a vassal of the devotees of the Lord, enshrined in Tirukkaṇṇapuram?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
