<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;अधिप्राकृतम् on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;अधिप्राकृतम् on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/history/</guid>
      <description>The Dravidian language Tamil retains a large number of old loans from Maharashtri Prakrit, even though its descendent language Marathi does not. This suggests that the prakritic base of other IA languages were overlayed by a secondary layer derived from a later degeneration of Sanskrit. This secondary layer is actually a Pan-Indian phenomenon and could represent the point of normalization of the Pan-Indian Sanskritic elite with respect to the Prakritic masses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syed Ahmed and Urdu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/syed-ahmed_and_urdu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/syed-ahmed_and_urdu/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
Thread by @bhAratenduH on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App
Sir Syed Ahmed Khan was for “united India” as long as Hindus were to accept Muslim supremacy as it was during Sultanate. Why would Indian Muslims want a separate territory when they can get the whole India? This “change” in SSAK came when he saw no hope for Indian Muslims to be able to achieve that, noticing the rising tide of Hindu revival, with a sophisticated Svadeshi movement with Bengal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UP hindI urdu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/UP-hindI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/UP-hindI/</guid>
      <description>Source: sarvesh
~90% of UP vocabulary comes from Sanskrit-Prakrit:
tatsama 25% tadbhava 50% deshaja 15% The rest 10% are loan words, most of which modified to indigenize.
The number 90% is the estimate of a scholar who studied UP’s speech.
As per Urdu lexicographers like Rauf Parekh and Syed Ahmed Dehlavi, 99% of Urdu verbs and 75% of Urdu words come from Sanskrit and Prakrit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urdu fall</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/urdu-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/urdu-fall/</guid>
      <description>Source: TW
I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why some people are against Urdu. It is Indian language, though not as old as Sanskrit, Tamil or Hindi but still it originated in India.
It is a common question. So, let me tell you why is the problem and ignorance towards Urdu.
In mid 19th century, Mughal Empire ended and all of its bureaucracy, employees started Urdu movement. In that, they wanted Urdu as official language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>उच्चारण-परिवर्तनम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/uchchAraNa-parivartanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/uchchAraNa-parivartanam/</guid>
      <description>ह्रस्व-दीर्घ-व्यत्ययः मराठीभाषायाम् ते त॑त्समश॒ब्दान् अपि॒ यथापि॑ लिखि॒तान् स्वैर् म॑राठीभाषानिय॒मैर् ह्र॑स्वदीर्घव्यत्य॒येन॑ पठन्ति। ते च॒ तेषां॑ निय॒मा अर्थं॒ नाव॑धारयन्ति। श॒ब्द॒स्व॒रू॒पा॒नु॒सा॒रम् ए॒व ह्र॑स्वदीर्घ॒त्वं विधी॑यते। शब्दे॑ ह्रस्वदीर्घ॒त्वं कथ॑यितुं॒ काऽपि॒ स्मृति॒र् नापे॑क्षिता। हि॒न्दी॒भा॒षां वद॒न्तोऽप्यन॑भ्यासे॒ तथै॒व म॑राठीनिय॒मैर् ह्र॑स्वदीर्घ॒त्वं कृ॒त्वा व॑दन्ति। अ॒न्यस्य॑ हिन्दीभा॒षां श्रु॒त्वा कथ॑यितुं॒ न श॑क्नुवन्ति॒ यत्र॑ ह्र॒स्वो यत्र॑ च दी॒र्घः। अत॑ उच्यते ह्रस्वदीर्घत्वाविवे॒क इति॑। अपि॑ च तत्समश॒ब्दानां॒ लेख॑ने मराठ्यनुसा॒रं व्य॑त्य॒यं दृ॒ष्ट्वैवेमे ले॑खननिय॒माः कृ॒ताः। लिखननियमा अत्र । तथापि॒ सर्व॑स्मिन् महारा॒ष्ट्रे गु॑र्जरप्रदे॒शे विद॑र्भेषु॒ क्व॑चिन् मध्यप्रदे॒शे क॑र्णाटप्रदे॒शेऽपि॑ च (क॒न्न॒ड॒लि॒प्या) लि॑खि॒तेषु॑ तत्समश॒ब्देषु॑ व्यत्य॒यं प॑श्याम्ये॒व। To specify more details, the variation of vowel length in Marathi poetry occurs primarily in इ/ई and उ/ऊ.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
