<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;03 - Third Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;03 - Third Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Mutic coti</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/01_Mutic_coti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/01_Mutic_coti/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.1 In the end-stanza of the preceding decad, the Āḻvār had referred to himself as one possessed of a clear vision, absolutely free from doubt and despair, discrepancies and deviations. But in the very next song, that is, the first song of this decad, he seeks clarification of certain doubts and thus betrays his ignorance. Well, ignorance is of four different kinds, namely (1) Non-comprehension. (2) comprehension, halfway beset with doubts, (3) miscomprehension and (4) lapse of memory resulting in not remembering a thing previously known.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Munnir nalam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/02_Munnir_nalam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/02_Munnir_nalam/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.2 We have only to imagine the pangs of a person unable to quench his extreme thirst, notwithstanding the availability of plenty of water near at hand, just because his mouth is sealed up (like Tantalus in the Greek legend). We will then be able to appreciate the most unenviable predicament in which the Āḻvār found himself, suffering from the figurative lock-jaw. Here is the Lord in His worshiṛpable form, of insatiable beauty, near at hand, and yet, the Āḻvār is not able to comprehend and enjoy Him as well as He would like to, severely handicapped as he is, by the heavy limitations inherent in his earthly existence, tethered to this material body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Olivu il kalam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/03_Olivu_il_kalam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/03_Olivu_il_kalam/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.3 The Āḻvār prayed to the Lord that his body, the material shackle, which stood in the way of his enjoyment of the Lord, be cut out. But then, the Lord pacified the Āḻvār by pointing out that this body of the Āḻvār in which the Lord eventually got hold of him was by-no-means an impediment, as he thought it to be. On the other hand, He literally coveted him, in that very body, and very much desired to take service from him, in his present embodied state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Pukalum nal oruvan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/04_Pukalum_nal_oruvan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/04_Pukalum_nal_oruvan/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.4 In the preceding decad, the Āḻvār was all agog to serve the Lord, at all times and in every conceivable manner, without break or blemish. Profoundly impressed by the intensity of the Āḻvār’s yearning for Divine service, the Lord very much wished to make his task easy and so threw into focus His unique faculty of omnipresence, pervading all things, all over and at all times. Coming face to face with the Lord’s immense ubiquity in various forms, the Āḻvār was in the same predicament as the one gathering the fruits dropped down the trees in a violent gale, finding it difficult to pick and choose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Moym mam pum polil</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/05_Moym_mam_pum_polil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/05_Moym_mam_pum_polil/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.5 In the last decad, we saw the Āḻvār enjoying the Lord’s immanence in quite a marvellous way. So ecstatic and love-smitten did he become on beholding the Lord’s ‘Vibhūti’, vast and varied, immense and interesting, defying description, that he was thrown into the rapturous state of singing and dancing. One has only to witness a Saint in his moments of rapturous ravishment in union with God, moments when his whole being thrills with love and his eyes swim with the pearls of tears of delight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Ceyya Tamaraik Kannan Ay</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/06_Ceyya_Tamaraik_Kannan_Ay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/06_Ceyya_Tamaraik_Kannan_Ay/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.6 In the preceding decad, the Āḻvār extolled the devotees thrown into a state of ecstasy, enraptured by the contemplation of the Lord’s wondrous deeds and auspicious traits, moving about, all the time singing and dancing. In the same breath he spoke disparagingly of those who do not exhibit this kind of behaviour but remain callously indifferent, unmoved by and impervious to the glory of the Lord. But then, the Āḻvār, known for his deep compassion and love for the fellow-beings, wished to bring round even those in the latter category and impress, in their mind, the Lord’s extraordinary trait of tender solicitude and easy accessibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Payilum Cutar oti</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/07_Payilum_Cutar_oti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/07_Payilum_Cutar_oti/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.7 Despite his earlier disappointments, it was his extraordinary fellow-feeling that egged the Āḻvār on, to address the worldlings once more, as in the last decad, pretty sure of bringing them round. Even the amazing simplicity of the Lord in His ‘Arcā’ manifestation, the sure plank, according to the Āḻvār, for weaning them, made no visible impact on the unfortunate fellows wallowing in the sty of worldly life, much to the chagrin of the Āḻvār.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Mutiyane</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/08_Mutiyane/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/08_Mutiyane/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.8 While trying to sustain himself by recounting the glory of the Bhāgavatas (Lord’s devotees), as in the last decad, the Lord’s glorious traits and wondrous deeds were also dwelt upon, side by side, in each stanza of that decad, in view of the irresistible appeal of the latter. It may also be recalled that, in III-6-10 we could notice the Āḻvār’s deep anxiety to behold the Lord’s pair of legs dangling down the chariot on the battlefield at Kurukṣetra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Connal Virotam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/09_Connal_Virotam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/09_Connal_Virotam/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.9 (1) Among the myriads of the Lord’s Creatures the human form is a rare gift of the Lord. Even so, the human form, thus dowered, has to be free from physical and mental handicaps. Even then, acquisition of a high degree of learning is rare and rarer still is the capacity for writing Verses. And then again, this extremely rare gift of verse-making has to be put to proper use but, more often than not, this talent is prostituted for the poet’s selfish ends, by indulging in praise of the petty humans, as, for example, the Sanskrit work, entitled ‘Pratāpa Rudrīyam [Rudṛyaṃ]’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Canmam Palapala</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/10_Canmam_Palapala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/03_-_Third/10_Canmam_Palapala/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro3.10 The Lord is most eminently suited for laudation by virtue of His innumerable auspicious traits, wondrous deeds and vast possessions. And yet, the worldlings would not listen to the Āḻvār’s advice, as in the preceding decad, to praise Him exclusively and desist from praising others. The Āḻvār, however, felt happy that he could at least get back from them unscathed without following in their footsteps. That spirit of complacence tuns through this decad also with an extra gusto.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
