<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;01 - First Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;01 - First Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Uyarvu ara Uyar Nalam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/01_Uyarvu_ara_Uyar_Nalam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/01_Uyarvu_ara_Uyar_Nalam/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.1 [Note: This work comprises ten centums, or hundred decades, each of which is called a ‘Tiruvāymoḻi’, which means ‘Inspired utterance’ as well as ‘Divine speech’, the speech from the holy mouth of the Saint. This is a skilled poetic composition in which each stanza begins with the closing word of the previous stanza or the phonetic sound thereof. Unlike the other hymns of the ‘Divya Prabandha’, Tiruvāymoḻi is accorded the special status of being chanted only inside the temples or at homes when the Deity is seated for congregational worship, and not when the Deity is taken out in the streets in ceremonial precession.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Vitumin murravum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/02_Vitumin_murravum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/02_Vitumin_murravum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.2 The transcendental glory of the Supreme Lord, His Supremacy as the material cause as well as the efficient cause and final cause of all life and being, the fact of His being the one and only Giver, either directly or through other minor deities, whose favours their respective votaries seek. His lustrous Feet being the sure and certain means of salvation for one and all, all these having been revealed to the Saint by the Lord Himself, the Saint revelled in this blissful knowledge, in the preceding Tiruvāymoḻi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Pattu utai Atiyavar</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/03_Pattu_utai_Atiyavar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/03_Pattu_utai_Atiyavar/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.3 In the first decad of this centum, the Āḻvār spoke of the Super-eminent glory of the Lord and, in the very next decad, he exhorted the worldlings to turn their minds God-ward and get absorbed in Him, with whole-hearted devotion. But then, they felt that they were no better than the man, lame of both hands, being required to mount an elephant. Now, in this decad, the Āḻvār puts them at ease by depicting the disarming simplicity of the Lord, like unto an elephant making itself so pliable as to enable even such a lame man to mount it easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Am ciraiya mata naray</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/04_Am_ciraiya_mata_naray/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/04_Am_ciraiya_mata_naray/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.4 The Sublime and the Sensual have always co-existed in both the worlds-the mundane and the spiritual. There is, however, a fundamental difference in their inter-relationship, in the respective spheres. In the material world, the two are mutually exclusive, being diametrically opposed to each other. In the spiritual world, that which, in the language of aesthetics, is termed as ‘Śṛṅgār’, is nothing but the psychological imperative for man’s consciousness moving towards Him (Super-Soul) of ravishing beauty (as Bhāgavatā bears out), just the very inversion of the skin-deep, carnal variety of lust, stamping out the human lover-beloved union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Vala el ulakil mutalaya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/05_Vala_el_ulakil_mutalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/05_Vala_el_ulakil_mutalaya/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.5 In each of the preceding four decads, the Āḻvār has highlighted a particular trait of the Lord. These are exaltation (transcendent glory), Worship-worthiness, easy-accessibility (saulabhya) and forgiveness, respectively. In this decad, the Saint brings into focus the Lord’s condescension (sauśīlya), mixing freely with the lowliest, the crowning trait of the Lord, heading the list of sixteen traits mentioned by Śrī Vālmīki, in his poser at the very beginning of Rāmāyaṇa1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Parivatu il icanai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/06_Parivatu_il_icanai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/06_Parivatu_il_icanai/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.6 Following the pattern, hitherto noticed, of bringing to the fore a particular auspicious trait of the Lord in each decad (Tiruvāymoḻi), ‘Swārādatva’ (i.e.) easy worshippability of the Lord is emphasised in this decad. Unlike the minor deities whom it is very hard to propitiate, what with the sacrifice of goats and hens and other such harsh demands on their votaries, the Lord is pleased with whatever is offered to Him lovingly, with pious will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Piravittuar ara</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/07_Piravittuar_ara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/07_Piravittuar_ara/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.7 Easy worshippability apart, the Lord should also be adorable.. We see around quite a few persons whom it is easy to please but we don’t like to court as there is nothing attractive or prepossessing in them. This decad shows that the Lord is highly adorable because of His extraordinary sweetness. As Nampiḷḷai would have it, the Lord is adorable to such an extent that He grows envious of His devotees and wants to adore them, in turn, having Himself tasted the sweetness of adoration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Otum pul eri</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/08_Otum_pul_eri/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/08_Otum_pul_eri/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.8 In this decad, the Āḻvār brings to the fore the Lord’s quality of ‘Uprightness’ (ārjava or rujuḥ), His transparence in word, deed and thought, free from sophistry, duplicity, mental reservation, mischievous distortion etc. The Lord would not mean one thing, say another and do a third thing. When Sūrpaṇakhā saw Śrī Rāma at Pañcavaṭi and interrogated Him about His personal history, there would have been nothing wrong if He had tactfully withheld the truth from the demoness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Ivaiyum avaiyum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/09_Ivaiyum_avaiyum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/09_Ivaiyum_avaiyum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.9 If the Lord’s flow of grace unto the hitherto starved Soul were to be full and flooding, all of a sudden, the Subject cannot stand it and will just get swept off his feet. It is a matter of common knowledge how babes are fed through a graded course, beginning with breast milk, a little gruel some time later, and then, small bits of rice and so on. If, out of misplaced love, a parent fed the young one straightaway on adult scale-rice, curry and all that—the result would be disastrous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Poru ma nil patai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/10_Poru_ma_nil_patai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/01_-_First/10_Poru_ma_nil_patai/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro1.10 In this decad, the Lord‘s voluntary or spontaneous grace is prominently brought out and extolled by the Āḻvār. Some Ācāryas, however, hold that the Āḻvār gives vent to his boundless joy resulting from the Lord‘s contact with him, limb by limb, mentioned in the preceding decad. The remarkable approach of Śrī Parāśara Bhaṭṭar, that intellectual giant of extraordinary divine fervour to this decad is as follows:
In the preceding decad, the Supreme Lord was shown to have finally got on to the Āḻvār’s head.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
