<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;06 - Sixth Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;06 - Sixth Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Vaikal pun kalivay</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/01_Vaikal_pun_kalivay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/01_Vaikal_pun_kalivay/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.1 We saw in the preceding centum from V-7 and onwards the Āḻvār seeking refuge in successive Pilgrim centres, at the feet of the Lord enshrined there. If the surrender at the feet of the Lord which should yield the result as a matter of course, did not meet with immediate response from the Lord, it was because He willed that the contemporary world as well as posterity should benefit through the Āḻvār’s scintillating hymns flowing from his sweet lips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Min itai matavarkal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/02_Min_itai_matavarkal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/02_Min_itai_matavarkal/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.2 In this decad, the Āḻvār strikes an entirely new note, making a bold departure, rather, in refreshing contrast to the earlier ones. The Saint, who was hitherto pining for the Lord’s presence and crying out his heart, now keeps Him at bay, when He eventually turns up in post-haste (even as He rushed to Gajendra’s aid) in response to the Nāyakī’s piteous appeal in the last decad, conveyed to the Lord through her special emissaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Nalkuravum, Celvum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/03_Nalkuravum_Celvum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/03_Nalkuravum_Celvum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.3 In VI-1, the Saint sent messages to Lord Rāma at Tiruvaṇvaṇṭūr but He responded, rather late. This made the Nāyakī furious and she enacted, in the preceding decad, all that tussle, which ensued between Śrī Kṛṣṇa and the Gopīs. Ultimately, the Lord proved victorious, as seen in VI-2-10, and the reunion between Him and the Saint materialised. The Saint now keeps musing over the superior might of the Lord, in having weaned him round, despite his stout resolve not to have anything to do with that malingering defaulter any more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Kuravai aycciyarotu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/04_Kuravai_aycciyarotu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/04_Kuravai_aycciyarotu/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.4 In the last decad of the last centum, the Āḻvār wished to sustain himself by contemplating the Lord’s wondrous deeds during His Avatāras but literally broke down, overwhelmed by emotion. It was with deep sorrow, born of frustration, he then gave vent to his inability to steady himself and recount the Lord’s deeds, mighty and miraculous. But the picture which has now emerged, is vastly different, the erstwhile emotional break-down and exhaustion yielding place to exhilaration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Tuval il ma mani matam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/05_Tuval_il_ma_mani_matam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/05_Tuval_il_ma_mani_matam/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.5 The theme of Nāyakī, Mother and Mate, that is, the Āḻvār expressing himself in the vein of a female lover, her mother and mate, by turns, has already been dealt with, in extenso, in the preamble to 1-4. Of the hundred decads, comprised in this work, as many as seventeen reflect the ‘Nāyakī’ aspect, seven are put in the mouth of the Mother and three voiced forth, by the mates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Malukku, vaiyam alanta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/06_Malukku_vaiyam_alanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/06_Malukku_vaiyam_alanta/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.6 The last decad was put in the mouth of the mates of Parāṅkuśa Nāyakī, while, in the current decad, it is her mother who speaks out the desperate condition of her love-lorn daughter. The manner in which the Nāyakī is dwindling down, losing, one by one, her feminine charms and embellishments, is set out, stanza by stanza. As a matter of fact, in IV-8 ante, these very things which now get dropped off, were despised by the Nāyakī, as not worth possessing, insofar as they had no bearing on Divine Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Unnum Coru, Parukum nir</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/07_Unnum_Coru_Parukum_nir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/07_Unnum_Coru_Parukum_nir/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.7 The mother continues her narration, in this decad also. She lay beside her love-lorn daughter, soothing her, as best as could be done. But suddenly, the mother groped the bed next to hers and discovered that her daughter was not in it. The former searched for the latter, high and low, but in vain. The mother was, however, well aware of her daughter’s exuberance of love for the Lord, enshrined at Tirukkōḷūr and, therefore, rightly concluded that the Nāyakī should have gone there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Pon-ulaku aliro</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/08_Pon-ulaku_aliro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/08_Pon-ulaku_aliro/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.8 This is yet another decad, where the Āḻvār sends messages to the Lord through birds, bees etc, the two earlier ones being I-4 and VI-1. This is the third such decad and the fourth and the last decad of this kind is IX-7, The technique, in this regard, having been already elucidated in the preamble to I-4, it would suffice if the distinguishing feature of this decad is brought out, namely, the message is now sent to the Lord in His ‘Para’ or transcendent and ‘Antaryāmi’ or hidden Form, as Internal Controller of all, as could be gathered mainly from Stanzas 4 and 5 of this decad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Nir ay nilan ay</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/09_Nir_ay_nilan_ay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/09_Nir_ay_nilan_ay/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.9 The Lord did not present Himself before the Āḻvār in spite of the errands run by his emissaries, as in the last decad. The Āḻvār, therefore, decided to raise his own clarion call of deep yearning, reaching the very Heavens, with robst faith in the fruition of his full-throated call for deliverance. It would indeed be well-nigh impossible for the Lord to stay in Heaven, once the Āḻvār’s voice is heard by Him, over there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Ulakam unta Peruvaya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/10_Ulakam_unta_Peruvaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/06_-_Sixth/10_Ulakam_unta_Peruvaya/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro6.10 In the last decad, the Āḻvār voiced forth, in deep anguish, his inordinate longing for communion with the Lord, so as to be audible to Him, right in Heaven. And yet, there has been no response from the Lord and the Āḻvār is, therefore, in a state of extreme mental distress and physical debility. He is, however, quick to realise that the Lord stands enshrined in holy Tiruvēṅkaṭam (Andhra Pradesh), the common meeting ground of the ‘Nitya Sūrīs’ (Eternal Heroes in Heaven), the ‘Nitya Samsārīs’ (worldlings), birds and beasts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
