<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;09 - Ninth Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;09 - Ninth Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Konta pentir</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/01_Konta_pentir/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/01_Konta_pentir/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.1 In the last decad (8-10), the Āḻvār had revealed to us the quintessence of his creed, namely, looking upon the Lord’s devotees as his ‘Be-all’ and ‘End-all ‘All-in-one the sole means for attaining ‘Mokṣa’ (Salvation). The Saint is further elaborating it, in this decad. in a manner highly delectable to the devotees, in whom he has taken refuge. The superficial reader might think that this decad strikes a note different from that of the immediately preceding decad inasmuch as the Āḻvār now looks upon the Lord as the aggregate of all conceivable kinship, one can claim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Pantai nalale</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/02_Pantai_nalale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/02_Pantai_nalale/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.2 The inviolable and eternal bond between us and the Supreme Lord, Who combines in Him the different facets of earthly relationship known to us, was stressed upon in the last decad, incidentally throwing overboard our so-called relationship with all the rest. The Upaniṣads proclaim that the Lord is “All-in-one”, “Mātā Pitā, Brātā, Nivāsaś Śaraṇam Suhrut gathir Nārāyaṇa”. Actually, He stays in His ‘Arca’ (iconic) Form, in the pilgrim centre known as Tiruppuḷiṅkuṭi, only to extend to His votaries all the benefits which they could expect from their earthly relations, mother, father, brother etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Or ayiramay</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/03_Or_ayiramay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/03_Or_ayiramay/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.3 In the last decad, the Āḻvār fervently prayed that the Lord be pleased to turn His sweet glances on him, grant audience to him and the denizens of all the three worlds, remaining in a seated posture, beckon him or come down to him and permit him to stroke His lovely pair of feet and so on. The Lord, however, focussed the Saint’s attention on the fundamental relationship that subsists between them, which hardly affords scope for such entreaties by him and, much less, for the grief that results from the Lord’s apparent non-compliance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Maiyar Karunkanni</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/04_Maiyar_Karunkanni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/04_Maiyar_Karunkanni/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.4 The ‘Śāstras’ (Scriptural texts) proclaim, on the one hand, that the Supreme Lord is One of unbridled independence, and on the other, depict Him as an embodiment of innumerable auspicious traits. The latter get submerged when the former holds sway. But when the Lord’s independence gets subdued through the irresistible spell cast by Mahā Lakṣmī’s personal magnetism and the persuasive eloquence of Her pleadings, the auspicious qualities denoted by His name, ‘Nārāyaṉa’, become pronounced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Innuyirc cevalum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/05_Innuyirc_cevalum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/05_Innuyirc_cevalum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.5 The Lord pulled the Āḻvār out of his erstwhile dejection, by reminding him of the great felicity, conferred by Him. This refers to the Āḻvār’s great role in singing these hymns for the delectation of the devout. The Āḻvār also felt gratified that it was indeed a great gift of the loving Lord and this sustained the Āḻvār for the time being, as we saw in the last decad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Urukumal nencam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/06_Urukumal_nencam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/06_Urukumal_nencam/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.6 In the tenth song of the last decad, the Āḻvār’s declaration that he had joined his Lord in Heaven and that his physical frame, left behind, would also fall off in a day or two, might make one feel that it marked the end of his stay in this abobe. And yet, the Āḻvār remained inside the hollow of the sacred tamarind tree for quite some time and sang some more of these nectarean hymns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Em Kanal Akam</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/07_Em_Kanal_Akam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/07_Em_Kanal_Akam/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.7 The Āḻvār sustained himself, in a way, by contemplating the Lord’s auspicious traits, as in the last decad. In the process, he, however, developed a deep yearning for direct perception of the Lord. This led him on to send emissaries to the Lord to come down and grace him with His presence. And now, here is the last of the four decads in which messages were sent to the Lord by the Āḻvār, figuratively transformed as a forlorn female lover, the other three being I-4, VI-1 and VI-8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Arukkum vinaiyayina</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/08_Arukkum_vinaiyayina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/08_Arukkum_vinaiyayina/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.8 In the last decad, the Saint despatched several messengers to the Lord at Tirumūḻikkaḷam and yet, he could hardly contain the effervescence of God-love in him. He could not patiently await the return of the emissaries from the Lord and so, he tried to sustain himself by meeting the Lord enshrined in Tirunāvāy (another pilgrim centre in Kerala State, the number of such pilgrim centres in that State adding up to thirteen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Mallikai Kamal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/09_Mallikai_Kamal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/09_Mallikai_Kamal/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.9 Our great preceptors used to call this decad, as the ‘Evening brawl’ and the third decad in the next (tenth) centum, as the ‘Morning squabble’. In the latter decad, the Āḻvār enters the vein of the Gopis, the damsels of Virundāvaṉ, who quarrelled with Kṛṣṇa early in the morning when he was about to take the cattle to the pastures for grazing, dissuading him from going to the outlying fields, in view of their inability to brook separation from him for a whole day, not to speak of the lurking danger from Kaṃsa’s spies and evil agents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Malai nanni</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/10_Malai_nanni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/09_-_Ninth/10_Malai_nanni/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro9.10 In the eighth decad of this Centum, the Āḻvār exhibited his inordinate longing for communion with the Lord and his great grief, due to the non-realisation of the union longed for, found expression in the following decad. Seeing the Āḻvār, in such dire distress, the Lord spoke to him thus: “Well, your grief apart, mine is indeed greater than yours, inasmuch as I have not, as yet, got at you and the privation is mine; it is only for your sake that I have come down, all the way, from the High Heavens to the holy centre of Tirukkaṇṇapuram, near at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
