<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maharatti and Kannada and more musing on Indo-Aryan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-16_maharatti-and-kannada-and-more-musing-on-indo-aryan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-16_maharatti-and-kannada-and-more-musing-on-indo-aryan/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
Obivously, Indo-Aryan and Dravidian have been at the center of my linguistic interests because they are the very basis of my cultural and genetic heritage. During my peregrinations in the peninsula I made some observations, and read a work of KM Munshi that the muni brought to my attention, which resulted in a flash. This concerns the relationship between Maharatti the Indo-Aryan language of the northern peninsula and the Aryanized Dravidian language Kannada that is a bit further south.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The substrate in Old Indo-Aryan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-16_the-substrate-in-old-indo-aryan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-16_the-substrate-in-old-indo-aryan/</guid>
      <description>Source: here.
Over the past century Western as well as Hindu investigators have noted the substrate in Indo-Aryan. However, identifying its origin has been largely left to the speculative whims of the worker. Dravidian and Austro-Asiatic have been the pet choices, but there are serious problems with each of these. A proper objective reconstruction of native proto-Dravidian has not been carried out to discern true transfers from Dravidian to IA. There is a heavy weighting favor of Tamil- but then Tamil is not proto-Dravidian and Tamil was influenced prior to its earliest attestation by IA.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
