<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;04 - Fourth Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;04 - Fourth Centum on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Oru nayakamay</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/01_Oru_nayakamay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/01_Oru_nayakamay/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.1 The last centum ended on a very happy note, an exuberant Āḻvār, gratefully conscious of the felicities showered on him by a loving Lord, declaring that he is above wants of any kind and free from afflictions of any kind. Just the opposite is, however, the plight of the ‘Saṃsāris’ (worldlings), and it was out of an irrepressible fellow-feeling and deep compassion that the Āḻvār tried to bring them all, on a par with him and advised them in III-9 (coṉṉāl virōtam) to give up running after the petty humans and their petty wealth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 Palan ay, El ulaku untu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/02_Palan_ay_El_ulaku_untu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/02_Palan_ay_El_ulaku_untu/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.2 In the eighth decad of the third centum, the Āḻvār and his sense-organs intensely longed for the enjoyment of Ged, in a spirit of competitive exuberance. In the three succeeding decads, this God-hunger was temporarily displaced, partly by the Āḻvār’s preoccupation with his fellow-beings and partly by his joyous recounting of the various benefits conferred on him by the bounteous Lord. And now, in this decad, the Āḻvār’s God-hunger has lifted up its head once again, the recoiling, as it were, of the Āḻvār’s advice to the worḻdlingson the Āḻvār himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 Kovai Vayal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/03_Kovai_Vayal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/03_Kovai_Vayal/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.3 This decad would appear to have been appreciated in three different ways by the ‘Pūrvācāryas’ (Preceptors of yore), as indicated below:
Notes
(i) According to Empār, the Lord did not, as such, fulfil the aspiration of the Āḻvār, as set out in the preceding decad, but focussed his attention on some of His auspicious traits enjoying which the Āḻvār remains oblivious of his erstwhile longing. This is like the baby crying for the Moon being appeased by a substitute, say, a Coconut.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04 Mannai iruntu tulavi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/04_Mannai_iruntu_tulavi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/04_Mannai_iruntu_tulavi/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.4 In the last decad, the Āḻvār rejoiced, over head and ears, in the sweet contemplation of the connubial love subsisting between him and the Lord. The Lord, however, apprehended that the Āḻvār might be swept off his feet and thrown overboard by such exuberance of joy, the overwhelming divine ecstasy jeopardising one’s very existence. As already pointed out, at length, in the preamble to 1-9, He is known to regulate the flow of His grace, consistent with the recipient’s capacity for in-ṭake and He, therefore, brought down the tempo, a little, just to stabilise the Āḻvār’s God-enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05 Virriruntu el ulakum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/05_Virriruntu_el_ulakum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/05_Virriruntu_el_ulakum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.5 If the Āḻvār was seen in the last decad in a heavy state of depression, it was because the Lord intended it to be so. Even as hunger is the pre-requisite for consuming food, for God-enjoyment in its entirety, a consuming passion of the highest intensity, as seen in the climactic tenth decad of the tenth centum, is imperative. Meanwhile, what is happening is a course of Shock-treatment, working the Āḻvār up to the required pitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06 Tirpparai yam ini</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/06_Tirpparai_yam_ini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/06_Tirpparai_yam_ini/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.6 In the last decad, the Āḻvār was seen at the acme of divine bliss, bubbling with joy and fully satisfied. The Lord has, however, since withdrawn Himself from the Āḻvār’s mental vision and he is now consigned to the bottom-most depths of dejection, transformed once again as a ‘Nāyakī’, unable to speak out her woe. It is her mate that speaks, in this decad. Parāṅkuśa Nāyakī is thinning down alarmingly, in her present state of extreme desolation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07 Cilam illac ciriyan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/07_Cilam_illac_ciriyan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/07_Cilam_illac_ciriyan/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.7 The Āḻvār, who was insensate in the last decad, due to the poignancy of his separation from the Lord, just regained consciousness, when the holy names of the Lord, chanted by the women around, trickled down his ears. This is like a creeper, dried up and lying low, becoming green again, when rain-drops fall on it. But then, it has only made matters worse for the Āḻvār. While in a state of coma, the patient feels no pain but when he regains consciousness, the pain becomes all the more acute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>08 Eru alum Iraiyonum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/08_Eru_alum_Iraiyonum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/08_Eru_alum_Iraiyonum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.8 The Āḻvār’s passionate appeal to the Lord, in the last decad, did not yield the desired result. The Lord didn’t present Himself before the ardent devotee, and the latter, therefore, concluded that he was not in His good books. And, in this context, the Alvar felt that neither he nor his possessions deserved to exist. The very valuable Śāstraic meaning that anything, which hinders Divine Service and does not actively aid and participate in such service, deserves to be eschewed, is imparted in this decad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>09 Nannatar Muruvalippa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/09_Nannatar_Muruvalippa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/09_Nannatar_Muruvalippa/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.9 In the last decad, the Āḻvār got terribly vexed with himself and his possessions and wanted to give up his body, life, that and the other. But, even for this kind of dissolution, he had to depend upon the Lord’s help, as in the case of salvation. And so, he prays to the Lord to finish him off altogether. The Āḻvār’s ardour in this respect is remarkable. His longing to get out of this world is due to (1) frequent interruptions in communion with the Lord and the resultant pangs of separation, (2) intolerance of contacts with the worldlings, straying away from Him and (3) the cruel impact of the five senses and the domineering sense-organs, with the serious risk of his straying back into the domain of the sensual pleasures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Onrum-tevum, ulakum</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/10_Onrum-tevum_ulakum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/padyam/shrIvaiShNava/4k-divya-prabandha/sarva-prastutiH/23_tiruvAymoLHi_-_nammALHvAr_2791-3892/bhAShAntaram/satyamUrtiH/04_-_Fourt/10_Onrum-tevum_ulakum/</guid>
      <description>00 Intro4.10 The Āḻvār expressed his abhorrence of the ways of the world and lustily pleaded with the Lord, in the last decad, that he be removed at once from this infernal land. And yet, the Lord did not take him away but contrived to pacify him by exhibiting to him the heavenly splendour, right here, and to keep him on here. The Lord’s idea in doing so was to propagate, in this confounded world, the true knowledge about God-head, through the Āḻvār’s hymns, par-excellence, shorn of doubts, discrepancies and deviations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
